#### KARTIK SHAH

<u>kartik.isworking@gmail.com</u> | +91 987 065 9145 |Mumbai https://ikartiks.github.io/ | https://github.com/ikartiks |https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks

#### **Summary of Experience**

I have 6.3 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. Looking for an opportunity at New South Wales, Australia ( state sponsored PR holder, can shift ASAP ).

Android experience 6+ years
Javascript frameworks 3 years
Backend using Spring JPA & Hibernate or core PHP 2-3 years
Experience with Couch DB 1 year

#### Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

#### Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

#### **Technical Skills**

Strong: Android, Kotlin, Backbase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

### **Work Experience**

### OCT 2015 - OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

#### **HDFC Bank**

#### Responsibilities

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.9 \* rating.
- Build on top of Backbase native hybrid framework to provide logistic navigation from page A to page B.
- To provide native components and compatibility for bridging gap of native and hybrid application.
- To make app secure using reverse engineering tools and SSL Pinning.
- To collaborate with frontend, backend and 3<sup>rd</sup> party teams for optimal solutions to different banking requirements.
- To collaborate with stake holders from the bank for feature request to providing implementation solutions that best fit the banks needs as well as customer satisfaction.
- To guide both the Android & IOS teams regarding the solution implementation & best practices.
- End to end delivery for Android is my responsibility. Both teams are eventually led by Solutions architect.
- Optimization of apps for faster page rendering and 0 lag time.
- Building new native components and optimizing existing ones provided by Backbase to meet Bank's requirement.

### Environment

Google play console, Android Studio, Jenkins, Burp Suite, J-meter, Jira, GIT

## **Sony Pictures Entertainment**

### Responsibilities

- Built a hybrid app using phonegap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- I looked into the Javascript part of the same using Angular JS V1.5.x.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) and native mobile application for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR.
- I handled the support work for backend development as well as frontend development for minor requirement changes to
  existing project.

Environment Eclipse, JBoss, Jenkins, Pivotal Tracker

## Mar 2015 - Oct 2015, Freestone InfoTech Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

### Responsibilities

- Led & performed development & maintenance using server side using Spring, JPA, and Hibernate for EPM Ware project.
- Managed complete lifecycle of mobile app Vee Smart Home (VSH).
- Created services in PHP for consumption in mobile app.
- Entire design, development was done by me alone.
- I was the sole android developer in the company back then.

Environment Eclipse, GIT, Android Studio

#### Responsibilities

#### **Team Tracker**

- Led the development of this project.
- Handling a team of 2 other Android developers and 3 iOS developers
- Team Tracker was a product that helped us gain many customers as company's first product.
- It was built upon CouchDB, a noSql database which offered in built document sync and conflict resolution
- The app is a messaging and location tracking app for a corporate organization.

# Cakesnapp & Dr. Fixit

- Cakesnapp was a phonegap based hybrid application where as Dr Fixit was native hybrid.
- Handling a team of 2 other Android developers and 3 iOS developers
- Communicating with stakeholders for requirement gathering and implementation
- Collaborating with design teams to get the designs right for both the platforms.
- Cakesnapp was a professional contact sharing app.
- I was also a part of the frontend team to write Javascript for both the platforms.

Environment Eclipse, PHP, Phonegap GIT.

### May 2013 - Mar 2014, Megasys India Developer, Mumbai

#### Responsibilities

- Built, developed & designed complete lifecycle of 'IMSafe' mobile app, which was appreciated across states and within the
  media as well.
- This is a women safety app, and with the collaboration of regional police to show alerts.
- I managed end to end lifecycle of the app, and was the sole developer for this project.
- One of the links for its appreciation in media <a href="https://youtu.be/KzXYsg1rzrs">https://youtu.be/KzXYsg1rzrs</a>
- I was the sole android developer in the company back then.

Environment Eclipse.

### Feb 2012 - May 2013, Experience Commerce Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

# Responsibilities

- This is a digital marketing firm, and most apps made during the time were end customer based with the focus of customer acquisition. All the applications mentioned below except DNA, had the same core concept There is a campaign, and based on client specific needs, user has to add a photo and earn rewards for it. He may earn additional points for sharing the same on social media. At the end of the campaign users with most points are rewarded.
- Few exceptions included developing an app for USL which was store specific and hence never delivered to playstore. It was more of a display app to see the various offerings by USL.
- Built & developed apps for engaging brands like Britannia, Castrol cricket, IPL Team Royal Challengers Bangalore, United Spirits Limited, Adlabs Imagica and Daily News Analysis (DNA) newspaper.
- I have also written some of the PHP & frontend scripts for mobile in projects like iHealthU and CastrolCricket.
- I was the sole android developer back then.

# Environment Eclipse, PHP

# **Major Projects**

HDFC Bank	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.snapwork.hdfc	Android, Backbase, Kotlin
GRE Flashcards &	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Kotlin
Tests (My product)		
SPE – SmartR, Digital		Spring, Hibernate JPA,
Windows		AngularJS, Phonegap
EPMWare	http://epmware.com/	
<b>Home Automation</b>		Android, PHP
app		
Dr. Fixit	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit	Hybrid app development
Team Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker	Android, Couch database
ImSafe		Android
USL's RCB IPL Team	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android	Android, core JS, PHP
USL's Signature	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies	Android, core JS, PHP
Selfies app		
Britania's iHealthU	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge	Android, core JS, PHP
Adlabs Imagica	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark	Android, core JS, PHP
Castrol Cricket	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android	Android, core JS, PHP
EC Diwali cracker app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android	Android, core JS, PHP

# Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.